<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Gaurav Jhaveri</title>
 <link href="http://gauravjhaveri.com/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://gauravjhaveri.com/"/>
 <updated>2014-02-04T19:38:15+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://gauravjhaveri.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Gaurav Jhaveri</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Doing More, Doing Better</title>
   <link href="http://gauravjhaveri.com/doing-more.html"/>
   <updated>2014-01-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://gauravjhaveri.com/doing-more</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Doing More, Doing Better&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013 was a huge step forward for me. I learnt Ruby on Rails, among other things, from the ground-up by attending &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appacademy.io/&quot;&gt;App Academy&lt;/a&gt;. I also got my personal website up, which is something I&#39;ve wanted to do for a while. Finally, I got working on my first major project, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dotanexus.com/&quot;&gt;Dota Nexus&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn&#39;t matter what this project ultimately results in. The lessons learnt from the mistakes I made during the course of its development alone make it worth the time and effort I put in to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I know I can do more. And I can do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I signed-up for a number of MOOCs in 2013 but ended up dropping out of more than half of them. In some cases I merely wanted to explore the courses and see what they were about. On the other hand, there were some courses where I was over half-way to completion and dropped out because I started falling behind on the problem sets. So this year I&#39;m going to make a list of MOOCs I&#39;m interested in, and I&#39;m going to follow them through to completion. I&#39;ve already begun by enrolling in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/specialization/mobilecloudcomputing/2&quot;&gt;Mobile Cloud Computing with Android&lt;/a&gt; Specialization on Coursera. With a bit of better time-management than last year, I&#39;m confident I can learn a lot of new things this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Coding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dota Nexus was the only significant project I worked on in 2013. I didn&#39;t spend much time on side-projects or programming challenges and only spent a minimal amount of time implementing algorithms. This obviously resulted in my programming skills becoming rustier than I would have liked. I plan on changing that. I&#39;m going to try working on at least one side-project every week. I&#39;m also going to spend some time each day working on problems from &lt;a href=&quot;http://programmingpraxis.com/&quot;&gt;Programming Praxis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/dailyprogrammer&quot;&gt;/r/dailyprogrammer&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, I&#39;m going to regularly implement algorithms from CLRS as I read about them. All of this should go a long way in keeping my coding skills sharp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Events&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August 2013 was when I attended my first ever hackathon - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.554286037965737.1073741830.248745975186413&amp;amp;type=1&quot;&gt;Facebook Summer of Hack&lt;/a&gt; in New York City. I had done a lot of coding before that, but none of it was under so much pressure. It&#39;s supposed to be a fun event, right? But to be able to produce something in 24 hours so that you don&#39;t make a fool of yourself in front of all these smart people, that&#39;s stressful. Our team did less than stellar, but it was still one of the best experiences of my life. I&#39;m going to make it a point to attend more of these events and learn more from all the incredibly smart people in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m looking forward to 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello, world!</title>
   <link href="http://gauravjhaveri.com/hello-world.html"/>
   <updated>2013-10-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://gauravjhaveri.com/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Hello, world!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a long month. I needed a personal website up to showcase some of the projects I&#39;ve been working on while also getting some more experience in the process. What I thought would only be a week-long project ended up taking far, far longer than that. This was partly due to the fact that I hadn&#39;t quite planned things very well and also because I&#39;ve been overwhelmed with work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rails was a natural starting point because that&#39;s what I&#39;m most comfortable with. I could have used &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; but Rails allows me far more flexibility, in case I want to add features in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew that the bulk of my website was going to consist of static pages. I started out by creating a &#39;Pages&#39; controller and having a separate action for each page. This method worked fine, but it didn&#39;t seem very clean to me. That&#39;s when I found out about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/thoughtbot/high_voltage&quot;&gt;High Voltage&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://thoughtbot.com/&quot;&gt;ThoughtBot&lt;/a&gt;. High Voltage provides a neat, clean way to organize and serve static pages. It also handles the routes for you and provides helper methods. Furthermore, you don&#39;t have to worry about duplicating headers and footers because it yields the pages in to a customizable layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I had to add a blog. After doing a bit of research, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; seemed to be the obvious choice. So, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.engineyard.com/2012/introducing-bloggy-a-simple-way-to-add-a-jekyll-blog-to-any-rails-application&quot;&gt;Bloggy&lt;/a&gt; to add Jekyll to my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&#39;s about it. My site is far from complete. I still have to add my resume and also work on the project showcase page. Nonetheless, I&#39;m happy to have something out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you&#39;re interested, the source code is up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Mutinix/gauravjhaveri.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Hello, world!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>